同学们，你们好。
现在是二零二二年，初中毕业，即升学考试
英语听力测试试音时间。
现在开始试听。
Hello, International Friends Club.
Can I help you?
Oh, hello. I read about your club in the paper today.
And I thought I'd phone to find out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we are a sort of social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we are growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British actually.
And I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages.
You know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish. Tuesday, Italian.
Wednesday, German and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal and restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
Okay, well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
事因到此结束。
二零二二年初中毕业暨升学考试
英语听力测试现在正式开始，
请看听力测试第一节。
第一节。
听句子，选择与所听内容相符的图片。
每个句子读两遍。
1. Be confident.
And you can do well in the exam.
2. Please turn right when you see a supermarket.
3. We have dumplings for dinner at the spring festival eve.
4. We went to Gansu Library, yesterday afternoon.
5. 18 is my favorite number.
第二节：听句子，选择恰当的应答语。
每个句子读两遍。
6. Would you like some orange juice?
7. I don't feel well now, and I think I've had a bad cold.
8. How is the weather today?
9. Thank you so much for helping us.
10. Thank you so much for helping us.
10. Whose hairband is it?
3. 11. Hello Sam.
第三节：听对话及问题，
选择能回答所提问题的最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
Let's go to the zoo today.
What animals do you like best?
My favorite animals are
Question. What animals does Sam like best?
11. Hello Sam.
Let's go to the zoo today.
What animals do you like best?
My favorite animals are pandas.
What animals does Sam like best?
12. Steve, there's going to be a football game this afternoon.
Do you know when it starts?
Sure, I do.
It will start at half past four this afternoon.
Question. When will the football game start?
12. Steve, there's going to be a football game this afternoon.
Do you know when it starts?
Sure, I do.
It will start at half past four this afternoon.
Question. When will the football game start?
13. Hi, John.
Do you know who is the tall woman next to
That's her mother Tina.
Question. Who is Tina?
13. Hi, John.
Do you know who is the tall woman next to That's her mother Tina.
Question. Who is Tina?
14. What do you think of the life in Gansu, Batty?
I enjoy the time here.
People here are so friendly, and the food is amazing.
Question. How is Batty's life in Gansu?
14. What do you think of the life in Gansu, Batty?
I enjoy the time here.
People here are so friendly, and the food is amazing.
How is Batty's life in
15. you were late for the meeting just now.
You'd never been late.
What's up? Oh, there's something wrong with my car.
And I couldn't get a taxi, so I had to walk here.
Question. Why was David late for the meeting?
15. Question. Why was David late for the meeting?
16. Read the John Smith is a taxi driver.
第四节，听短文，根据其内容选择能回答下列问题的最佳答案。
短文读两遍。
But he can't go to work now, because he has been badly ill for more than three
months. He is still too weak to drive his taxi.
He lives in a small town with his wife and five children.
John's eldest son is 26.
He teaches in a village school.
He lives in the school, because it takes too long to travel there, every day from
his father's. The other children are not yet old enough to go out to work.
They still go to school, except his youngest son.
16. Question. Why was David late for the meeting?
Question. 17. Question.
第四节到此结束。
听力测试到此结束。
Listen